A Guide to the Papers of the Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia, 1927-1953
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Original Manuscripts-Round Table, Open Forum, Special Conference (Box 17-53)
  - Round Table: "The American Political Scene in 1936"
    - Introduction, Spencer Miller; "Background of the Current Political Scene," B. B. Kendrick; "The Economic Resources of America," Harold Loeb 1936 July 13 (Box 38)
    - "Address," William Hoster; "Beginnings of Political Research with Respect to Party Platforms and Policies," Professor Samuel McCune Lindsay; "The Place of Research in the Development of Government Policy," Mordecai Ezekiel; "The Place of Research as a Permanent Thing in Politics," T. N. Carver 1936 July 14 (Box 38)
    - "The Republican Platform and Program for 1936," H. M. Langworthy; "A National Platform and a National Philosophy of Government," Mrs. George A. Wyeth 1936 July 15 (Box 38)
    - "The Democratic Case, 1936," Honorable John Dickinson; "A Woman Looks at the Democratic Platform," Mrs. Thomas F. McAllister 1936 July 16 (Box 38)
    - "How Can We Develop an Informed Public Opinion in a Democracy?," Clyde L. King; "Problems in Public Welfare Administration," A. W. James 1936 July 18 (Box 38)
    - Summary of Speech, Norman Thomas; "Platform and Policy of the Communist Party in 1936," Earl Browder 1936 July 17 (Box 39)
    - "The Third Party Movement in 1936," Alfred M. Bingham; "The Political Education of the Electorate," Ben Howe; "Farmer Labor Party Views," Howard Y. Williams; Summary 1936 July 18 (Box 39)
  - Round Table: "Changing Asia"
    - "The Chinese Background," Dr. Cyrus H. Peake; "China in the Remaking" Dr. T. Z. Koo; "The Orient in the Western Literature," Younghill Kang 1936 July 13 (Box 39)
    - "Women in the Changing China," Eva B. A. Macmillan (Mrs. T. D. Macmillan); "Changing China from Within," Randolph T. Shields, M.D. 1936 July 14 (Box 39)
  - Evening Addresses
    - Introductory Statement 1936 (Box 39)
    - "America's Greatest Need," Rev. John McDowell, D.D., LL.D. 1936 July 5 (Box 39)
    - "What Is Wrong with the Nations?," Robert McElroy, Ph.D., LL.D., D.LITT.(Oxon.), F.R. Hist. S. 1936 July 6 (Box 39)
    - "The Stock Exchange and the Public Welfare," Charles R. Gay 1936 July 7 (Box 39)
    - "Taking Account of International Stock," M.E. Woolley; "Myth and Reality in International Economics,"Mrs. Barbara Frances Wootten 1936 July 8 (Box 39)
    - "Industrialism and the South," John Temple Graves II; "The Professions and the Economic Crisis," Walter Hampden; "An Appraisal of the Federal Social Security Act," Winthrop W. Aldrich 1936 July 9 (Box 39)
    - "Keeping the Investor Informed," Kenneth C. Hogate 1936 July 11 (Box 39)
    - Address, Dr. T. Z. Koo 1936 July 12 (Box 39)
    - "The Constitution of the United States," Honorable Stanley Reed 1936 July 13 (Box 39)
    - "The Constitution in the Light of Modern Trends," Henry W. Taft 1936 July 14 (Box 39)
    - "Relation of Government to Business," Alexander V. Dye; "The Campaign of 1936," Herman M. Langworthy 1936 July 15 (Box 39)
    - "Anglo American Censorship, Early and Late," Garrard Glenn 1936 July 16 (Box 39)
    - "Representative Government vs. Dictatorship," Hiram Bingham 1936 July 17 (Box 39)
  - Open Forum
    - "America and Europe," Frank O. Darva 1936 July 7 (Box 39)
    - "The Future of the League of Nations," C. F. Fenwick 1936 July 8 (Box 39)
    - "The Rise of Social Credit as a World Movement," Gorham Munson 1936 July 9 (Box 39)
    - "The Colonial Policy of the United States," Colonel Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. 1936 July 10 (Box 39)
    - "Apathy: The Chief Menace to Our Democracy," Ben Howe 1936 July 13 (Box 39)
    - "The Ideals and Aims of the Administration," John H. Fahey 1936 July 14 (Box 39)
    - "Historical Development of World Government," Professor Arthur W. Bromage 1936 July 15 (Box 39)
    - "The Responsibilities of Broadcasting in a Democracy," Frederic A.Willis 1936 July 16 (Box 39)
  - Round Table: "International Good Will"
    - "The Provincial Spirit as an Obstacle to Good Will," Spencer Brodney 1936 July 6 (Box 39)
    - Address, Fred R. Coudert; "Problems of Neutrality," P. W. H. Almy 1936 July 7 (Box 39)
    - "Debts as an Obstacle to Good Relations among Nations," Dr. William Wilson Cumberland 1936 July 8 (Box 39)
    - Press Release 1936 July 8 (Box 40)
    - "The Problem of Armaments," Brig. Gen. John Ross Delafield, Hugo E. Prager 1936 July 9 (Box 40)
    - "Economic Justice as the Basis of World Peace," Herbert S. Houston, Ph.D., M.A., LL.D. 1936 July 10 (Box 40)
    - "Social Credit and Political Action," Gorham Munson; "Talk Before Institute of Public Affairs," Frank P. Graham; "Human Relations," Ernest Minor Patterson 1936 July 11 (Box 40)
  - Round Table: "Current Problems in Our Latin American Relations"
    - Address, Dana G. Munro; "Twenty Five Years: A Glance at Inter American Progress," William A. Reid; "A Realistic Approach to Inter American Understanding," Professor Henry Grattan Doyle 1936 July 6 (Box 40)
    - "Present Economic Trends in Mexico," John B. Glenn; "Electrical Public Utilities in Mexico," Ernest Galarza 1936 July 7 (Box 40)
    - "Puerto Rico: Her Present and Future," Julio García Díaz; "Conditions in Puerto Rico," Otto Schoenrich 1936 July 8 (Box 40)
    - "A Latin American Investment," Dr. William Wilson Cumberland; "A Latin American Loan," Dr. William Wilson Cumberland; "Transportation Problems," Robert H. Patchin 1936 July 9 (Box 40)
    - "Trade Barriers: Latin American Variety," W. E. Dunn; Address, Henry L. Deimel, Jr. 1936 July 10 (Box 40)
    - "The Proposed Inter American Conference for the Maintenance of Peace," Donald R. Heath; "The Proposed Inter American Conference," Dr. Aldrin Racinos 1936 July 11 (Box 40)
  - Round Table: "Current Problems of Business and Finance"
    - Address, Robert M. Hanes; "Labor-Sound Money-Inflation," Matthew Woll; "Two Major Problems Affecting the Investor Today," Orrin G. Wood 1936 July 6 (Box 40)
    - "The Economic Functions of Speculation," Dr. William Wilson Cumberland; "The Functions of Speculation," Charles H. Meyer 1936 July 7 (Box 40)
    - "Credit Control," W. Randolph Burgess; "Control of Bank Credit," George V. McLaughlin; "Credit Control," Edmund Platt 1936 July 8 (Box 40)
    - "Capital Gains and Losses," Lovell H. Parker, Godfrey N. Nelson 1936 July 9 (Box 40)
    - "The Responsibilities of Corporate Management," C. M. Chester; "Erosion by Government Finance," Hon. Arthur A. Ballantine 1936 July 10 (Box 40)
    - "Investor Information: Its Economic Importance," Leland Rex Robinson; "The Securities Acts and the Investment Market," "Keeping the Investor Informed," William O. Douglas, Kenneth C. Hogate 1936 July 11 (Box 40)
  - Round Table: "Local Government"
    - Press Release, Professor Arthur Bromage; "County Home Rule in New York," Senator Thomas C. Desmond; "County Home Rule in Ohio," Professor Earl L. Shoup 1936 July 6 (Box 40)
    - "County Manager Plan in Operation," Roy S. Braden; "The County Manager Plan in Henrico County, Virginia," W. F. Day; "The County Manager Plan in Operation," H. A. Haden 1936 July 7 (Box 40)
    - Address, R. W. B. Hart; "The City Manager Plan in Operation," John N. Edy 1936 July 8 (Box 40)
    - "Problems of County Government in Relation to the South," Cullen B. Gosnell; "Problems of County Government Relative to the South," Professor Frank W. Prescott 1936 July 9 (Box 40)
    - "Functional Consolidation in the Counties of Virginia," Dr. Raymond Uhl; "County Consolidation in the South," John W. Manning 1936 July 10 (Box 40)
    - "The Place of the Survey in Political Science," John F. Sly; "Technique and Conclusions of the Pennsylvania Local Government Survey," Edward W. Carter 1936 July 11 (Box 40)
    - "Surveying Local Governments," Charles R. Erdman, Jr. 1936 July 11 (Box 41)
    - "Effect of Depression on State Local Relations," Howard P. Jones; "Federal City Relations," Morton L. Wallerstein 1936 July 13 (Box 41)
    - "Interstate Cooperation," Charles J. Calrow; "The Ability of Local Units to Finance Relief Costs," L. Lészló Ecker-R 1936 July 14 (Box 41)
    - "Conflicting Taxation with Special Reference to Local Finance," James W. Martin 1936 July 15 (Box 41)
    - "Personnel Administration in Cities and Counties," Oliver C. Short; "the Problem of Effective Personnel Administration in Small City Government," Maxwell Devoe 1936 July 16 (Box 41)
    - "Training for Public Administration," Professor J. R. Hayden 1936 July 17 (Box 41)
    - A.W. James (empty folder); "Problems in Public Welfare Administration," Frank Bane 1936 July 18 (Box 41)
  - Round Table: "The Church and the Problem of Democracy"
    - "Democracy's Judgement Day: Will It Stand?," Henry Smith Leiper 1936 July 6 (Box 41)
    - "The March of Democracy: Will It Halt?," Henry Smith Leiper 1936 July 7 (Box 41)
    - "The Foundations of Democracy: Are They Secure?," John A. MacCallum, D.D. 1936 July 8 (Box 41)
    - "The Meaning of Democracy: Has it a Definite Content?," John A. MacCallum, D.D. 1936 July 9 (Box 41)
  - Round Table: "Government and Business"
    - "Government and the Transportation Problem," E. L. Oliver 1936 July 14 (Box 41)
    - "Government and the Public Utilities," Siegfried F. Hartman; "The Federal Government and the Public Utilities," Basil Manly 1936 July 15 (Box 41)
    - "Government Regulation of Business," Rev. Wilfrid Parsons, S.J. 1936 July 17 (Box 41)
    - "Government in Business as a Political Issue," John Calvin Brown; "Social Legislation in Foreign Countries," W.L. Schurz 1936 July 18 (Box 41)
  - Special Conference: "Power Age Economics"
    - "The Flaw in the Price System," Paul Hampden; "Financing a Power Economy," Edward F. Harvey 1936 July 10 (Box 41)
    - "The Attack on Credit Monopoly from a Cultural Viewpoint," William Carlos Williams; "The Artist, the Audience, and Social Credit," James Laughlin IV 1936 July 11 (Box 41)
  - Special Conference: "The Emergency and the Long-Run in Education"
    - Announcement 1936 July (Box 41)
    - Address, Nathaniel Peffer 1936 July 15 (Box 41)
    - "Education in Germany," Gerold von Minden; "The Emergency in Italy," John Adams; "Perspectives in Soviet Education," Arthur Fletcher 1936 July 16 (Box 41)
    - "The Catholic Tradition in Education," W. H. McHugh 1936 July 17 (Box 41)
  - Special Conference: "Cooperative Education Association"
    - Address, William H. Bristow 1936 July 15 (Box 41)
  - Special Conference: "National Society of the U. S. Daughters of 1812"
    - Address, Mrs. William Armistead Porter 1936 Ju1 7 (Box 41)
  - Round Table: "Radio Symposium"
    - Transcript of Proceedings 1936 July 17 (Box 41)
  - Testimonial Dinner for Dr. Charles S. Maphis [10th anniversary of the founding of the Institute of Public Affairs]
    - Address, Dr. John McDowell, D.D. 1936 July 16 (Box 41)
  - Round Table: "Changing Asia"
    - "Background Influences in Modern Japan," Grover Clark; Address, M. Matsuo 1936 July 15 (Box 41)
    - "Japan's Trade Expansion: Its Effects on American Interests," Ben Dorfman; "Economic Japan Today," Dr. Elizabeth Boody 1936 July 16 (Box 41)
    - "Russia in Asia," Mrs. Kathleen Barnes; "Problems and Trends in Australia and New Zealand," Dr. Horace Belshaw 1936 July 17 (Box 41)
    - "Commodity Control in the Pacific," W. L. Holland 1936 July 18 (Box 41)
  - Round Table: "Government and Business"
    - "Government and the National Industrial Policy," Sullivan Jones; Address, J. G. Paine 1936 July 13 (Box 42)
    - "Government in Transportation," Robert S. Henry; "Air Transportation," Wiley R. Wright 1936 July 14 (Box 42)
  - Evening Addresses
    - "Faith as an Instrument of Liberation," Rev. John A. MacCallum, D.D. 1937 July 4 (Box 42)
    - Opening Remarks (including letter, dated June 29, 1937, read by Dr. Maphis from President Franklin D. Roosevelt), Dr. Charles G. Maphis; Hon. R. Walton Moore (empty folder) 1937 July 5 (Box 42)
    - "Religion's Contribution to the Abolition of War," Kirby Page; "Commercial Arbitration in the United States and Latin America," Herman G. Brock, Esq. 1937 July 6 (Box 42)
    - "Present Aspects of World Peace," Hon. Sumner Welles; Address, Hon. Key Pittman (empty folder) 1937 July 7 (Box 42)
    - "Business Can Safeguard World Peace," Hon. A. A. Berle, Jr.; Address, Edward Tomlinson, Esq. (empty folder) 1937 July 9 (Box 42)
    - "The Maintenance of Peace Otherwise Than Through the League of Nations," Luigi Villari 1937 July 10 (Box 42)
    - Vesper Services: "Religion and World Peace," Rabbi Eugene Kohn; "Outline of Remarks," Rev. M. Ashby Jones; and, "Religious Ideals for World Peace," Rev. Edward L. Stephens, D.D. 1937 July 11 (Box 42)
    - "Law Versus Chaos," Senator Elbert D. Thomas; "British Policy at Geneva," Sir Herbert Brown Ames, Kt.,LL.D. 1937 July 12 (Box 42)
    - "Does German Rearmament Necessarily Mean War?," Sir Herbert Brown Ames, Kt., LL.D.; "Is the Healthy Competitive Spirit of the German People an International Felony?," Dr. Helgo W. Culemann 1937 July 13 (Box 42)
    - "Avoiding War in the Pacific by Attending to our own Business," Major General Smedley D. Butler 1937 July 14 (Box 42)
    - "American Cultural and Philanthropic Enterprises in the Far East," Roger S. Greene, Esq. 1937 July 16 (Box 42)
  - Town Hall Debates
    - "Should There Be Federal Control of Wages and Hours?," James A. Emery and Hon. Hugo L. Black; "America's Town Meeting of the Air," National Broadcast Company 1937 July 15 (Box 42)
    - "Can America Remain Neutral?," Dr. Clark M. Eichelberger and Jerry H. Voorhis, Esq.; "America's Town Meeting of the Air," [transcript of radio broadcast] 1937 July 8 (Box 42)
  - Morning Addresses
    - "The Development of Modern Imperialism," Dr. Wolfgang Hallgarten 1937 July 6 (Box 42)
    - "Mass Action and Its Effect on... World Peace," Miss Jeannette Rankin 1937 July 8 (Box 42)
    - "The Second Partition of Palestine," Rabbi Maurice J. Bloom; "Sincerity the Only Path to Peace," J. Kenneth Bradley, Esq.; "World Peace Will Never be Disturbed by a Nation Whose People Are Correctly Informed as to the Rights of Other Nations ," Frank Wickhem 1937 July 10 (Box 42)
    - "International Relations from a Woman's Viewpoint," Dr. Anna Lane Linglebach 1937 July 12 (Box 42)
    - "National Defense Through Patriotic Education," Mrs. Vinton Earl Sisson 1937 July 14 (Box 42)
  - Round Table: "The Essential Conditions for International Security"
    - "Realization of the Major Aims of Rotary International," Rev. Paul D. Browden, D.D.; "The Relation of Currency Stabilization to International Security," Dr. William Wilson Cumberland 1937 July 5 (Box 42)
    - "The Common Sense of Most," Henry G. Ellis; "The Crucial Spot in International Relations," Dr. Frank Kingdon 1937 July 6 (Box 42)
    - "Obstacles to Peace," Charles W. Phillips, Esq.; "Obstacles to World Peace," Frederick R. Coudert 1937 July 7 (Box 42)
    - "The International Peace Campaign and Collective Security," William E. Dodd, Jr.; Summary of Address by Miss Helen Kirkpatrick 1937 July 8 (Box 42)
    - "The Individual, His Privileges, and His Responsibilities," William O. Tufts, Esq.; "Do the Peoples Desire War?," Spencer Brodney, Esq. 1937 July 9 (Box 42)
    - "Miscellaneous," transcript of discussion conducted by Dr. Robert McElroy 1937 July 1 (Box 42)
  - Round Table: "World Peace Through the Churches"
    - "Can the Church Contribute to the Establishment of a Cooperative and Warless World?," Rev. John A. MacCallum 1937 July 5 (Box 42)
    - "The Church in Action for World Peace," Harry N. Holmes, Esq. 1937 July 7 (Box 42)
    - "The Moral and Legal Bases of International Peace," Dr. Charles G. Fenwick 1937 July 9 (Box 42)
    - "The Historic Peace Mission of the Church," Rabbi William H. Fineshriber, D.D. 1937 July 10 (Box 42)
  - Round Table: "Inter American Relations"
    - "Three Views of Collective Security," Dr. Arthur Deerin Call 1937 July 5 (Box 43)
    - "The Influence of the American Institute of International Law Upon Inter American Relations," His Excellency, Senor Dr. Pedro Martínez Fraga 1937 July 6 (Box 43)
    - "Pan Americanism and World Peace," His Excellency, Senor Dr. Francisco Castillo Nájera 1937 July 7 (Box 43)
    - Address, Dr. Raul d'Eca (empty folder) 1937 July 8 (Box 43)
    - "Advancement of Peace Through Education," His Excellency, Senor Dr. Héctor David Castro 1937 July 9 (Box 43)
    - "The Rights of Women in Inter American Relations," Miss Doris Stevens 1937 July 10 (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous; Excerpts from an Interview with Dr. George Howland Cox 1937 July (Box 43)
  - Round Table: "Collective Security as a National Problem"
    - "National Insecurity: A Menace to World Peace," Dr. Samuel McCune Lindsay 1937 July 12 (Box 43)
    - "The Social Security Act: Its Accomplishments," Frank Bane, Esq. 1937 July 13 (Box 43)
    - "Social Change and Government Responsibility for Social Welfare," Miss Jane Hoey 1937 July 14 (Box 43)
    - "Government Responsibility Toward the Insecurity of Unemployment," R. Gordon Wagenet, Esq. 1937 July 15 (Box 43)
    - "Government Responsibility for Industrial Obsolescence and Old Age Dependency," Dr. John J. Corson 1937 July 16 (Box 43)
    - "The Future of Social Security in America," Dr. Arthur J. Altmeyer; Summary 1937 July 17 (Box 43)
  - Round Table: "Storm Centers in the Far East"
    - "The United States and the Philippine Commonwealth," Dr. Joseph Ralston Hayden 1937 July 12 (Box 43)
    - "Recent Phases in Indo British Relations," Dr. S. L. Joski 1937 July 13 (Box 43)
    - "China in 1937: Some Observations," Dr. Zhi Meng (Chih Meng) 1937 July 14 (Box 43)
    - "The Perennial Crises of Japan," T. Scott Miyakawa 1937 July 15 (Box 43)
    - "Contacts Between East and West," Grover Clark, Esq. 1937 July 16 (Box 43)
    - "American Policy in the Far East," Roger S. Greene, Esq. 1937 July 17 (Box 43)
  - Round Table: "International Organization for Collective Security"
    - "Excerpts from an Interview with Barnett Nover (Esq.)" 1937 July 12 (Box 43)
    - "The League of Nations' Record on Political Disputes," Dr. Pitman B. Potter; "The Non Political Activities of the League of Nations," Walter H. C. Laves, Esq. 1937 July 13 (Box 43)
    - Sir Herbert Brown Ames (empty folder) 1937 July 14 (Box 43)
    - Dr. Clark M. Eichelberger (empty folder); "Colonies and Raw Materials," Grover Clark, Esq. 1937 July 15 (Box 43)
    - "The International Labor Organization," Spencer Miller, Jr., LL.D. (Esq.); "A Constructive Tariff Policy," Dr. Leland Rex Robinson; "Cooperation vs. Isolation," Senator James P. Pope 1937 July 16 (Box 43)
    - "The United States and the League of Nations," Dr. Denna Frank Fleming 1937 July 17 (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous, "Part IV: The Little Entente," Sir Herbert Brown Ames 1937 July (Box 43)
  - Round Table: "Inter American Aspects of Economic Stability and Social Security"
    - "The New York World's Fair as an Instrument of Social Change," Mr. E. F. Roosevelt 1938 July 5 (Box 43)
    - "Our Trade with Latin America," Dr. Alexander V. Dye 1938 July 7 (Box 43)
    - "The Mexican People and the Oil Companies," Dr. Alejandro Carrillo; "Various Aspects of the Mexican Oil Confiscation," Major T. R. Armstrong 1938 July 8 (Box 43)
    - "Trade Development in Brazil," Senor Silvino da Silva 1938 July 9 (Box 43)
    - "Social Security in South America," Mr. William A. Reid 1938 July 13 (Box 43)
    - "Brazil and Pan American Social Security," Senorita Maria Pinheiro Guimaraes 1938 July 16 (Box 43)
  - Round Table: "International Good Will Through Economic Stability"
    - "Training the World Citizen," Mr. E. F. Phillips; "A European Danger Zone," Dr. Charles Pergler 1938 July 4 (Box 43)
    - "Blind Bridles," Mr. S. Wade Marr; "British Foreign Policy," Mr. John W. Wheeler Bennett 1938 July 5 (Box 43)
    - "International Stability and Institutional Status," Dr. Frank Kingdon; "Anarchy and International Good Will," Dr. Ernst W. Meyer 1938 July 6 (Box 43)
    - "The Instability of a System Under Protection," Dr. Giuseppe Ugo Papi; "Does International Finance Promote War or Peace?," Dr. William Wilson Cumberland 1938 July 7 (Box 43)
    - "Blocking New Wars," Dr Herbert S. Houston 1938 July 8 (Box 43)
    - "The Economic Aspects of Colonial Policy," Commendatore Luigi Villari; Summary 1938 July 9 (Box 43)
  - Round Table: "The Administration of the Social Security Program"
    - "How the Federal Government Functions in a Federal State System of Unemployment Compensation," Dr. George E. Bigge 1938 July 11 (Box 44)
    - Statement, Elmer F. Andrews; How the State Program Works," Major Frank P. Evans 1938 July 12 (Box 44)
    - "New Federal State Relationships," Mr. Frederic P. Lee 1938 July 13 (Box 44)
    - "The Cost of Administration of Unemployment Compensation," Dr. Herman Feldman 1938 July 14 (Box 44)
    - "The Extension of Coverage of Unemployment Compensation," Dr. Walter Gellhorn; "Health Hazards," Dr. Ewan Clague 1938 July 15 (Box 44)
    - "Constructive Proposals for Administrative Revision of Unemployment Compensation," Dr. Bryce M. Stewart; Summary 1938 July 16 (Box 44)
  - Round Table: "The Church Faces an Insecure World"
    - "Oxford and Edinburgh: From the Point of View of Youth," Rev. Clark V. Poling 1938 July 11 (Box 44)
    - "What Should Be the Interest of the Church in an Insecure World?" Father Edward H. Stephens; "The Church Faces an Insecure World," Rabbi William Greenberg; "The Interest of the Church in an Insecure World," The Rev. Holmes Rolston, Th.D. 1938 July 12 (Box 44)
    - "Relation of the Church to the State--Nationally and Internationally," The Rev. Henry Smith Leiper, D.D. 1938 July 13 (Box 44)
    - "The Contribution of the Church to Education," Bishop William W. Peele, D.D. 1938 July 14 (Box 44)
    - "Oxford Edinburgh: Moving Toward Unity," The Rev. Anson Phelps Stokes, D.D.; Summary 1938 July 16 (Box 44)
  - Round Table: "The Future of American Democracy"
    - "State and Local Government," Mr. Edgar F. Shannon, Jr.; "Relationship of Government to Agriculture," Mr. J. W. Green; "The Relation of Government to Business," Mr. George Shaskan, Jr.; "The Relation of Government to Agriculture," Mr. Edward M. Vinson; "State and Local Government," Mr. John T. Hermansen 1938 July 11 (Box 44)
    - "Relation of Government to Business," Mr. Charles F. Kiefer, Jr.; "The Future Peace of Democracy," Mr. Samuel K. C. Kopper 1938 July 12 (Box 44)
  - Round Table: "The Challenge of the Far East to World Security"
    - "The Far East: Some Historical Backgrounds," Dr. Paul Clyde 1938 July 11 (Box 44)
    - "How Strong Is Japan?," Dr. Elizabeth Boody Shumpeter 1938 July 12 (Box 44)
    - "What China Wants," Dr. Ch'ao ting Chi 1938 July 13 (Box 44)
    - "The Soviet Union and the Far East," Mr. Constantine Oumansky 1938 July 14 (Box 44)
    - "Economic and Social Conditions in Manchuria," Mr. Taneo Taketa 1938 July 15 (Box 44)
    - "British Economic Interests in the Far East," Mr. Herbert P. Elliston; "Japan in China as Viewed by a Japanese Subject," Mr. Taneo Taketa 1938 July 15 (Box 44)
    - "The Far East Challenges America," Dr. Edward R. Hume; Closing Remarks: Mr. Grover Clark 1938 July 16 (Box 44)
  - Morning Addresses
    - "Aims of the Republican Party," John Hamilton; "Democratic Objectives," Hon. Claude Pepper 1938 July 4 (Box 44)
    - "Equalizing Opportunity," Dr. Belle Boone Beard; "The Philippine Question," Mr. Vicente Villamin 1938 July 5 (Box 44)
    - "Recent Economic Trends," Hon. Clifton A. Woodrum; "The Place of the American Railroads in Our Economic Structure," Mr. R. V. Fletcher 1938 July 6 (Box 44)
    - "The Economic Situation in India," Dr. S. L. Joshi 1938 Ju1 7 (Box 44)
    - "Small Business Lifts Its Eyes," Mr. Alfred C. Gaunt 1938 July 8 (Box 44)